portphillippublishing.com.au 2019-03-07

# Privacy Policy - Port Phillip Publishing

**Port Phillip Publishing Privacy Policy**

Port Phillip Publishing takes individual privacy very seriously. We are also aware of the threats to your security and privacy. Please take a few moments to review the steps that Port Phillip Publishing takes to ensure your privacy and security while giving you the best possible customer service as you use our websites.

Our Privacy Policy outlines how we collect and handle your personal information. References to ‘PPP’, ‘we’, ‘our’ and ‘us’ refer to Port Phillip Publishing and its related companies.

**How and what personal information is collected?**

We collect your personal information (including your address, contact details, and credit card details) only when you place an order with us or when you contact us about your subscription or our other services. When you place an order, we will provide a secure (SSL, encrypted) connection and require you to submit only the information needed to complete and fulfill your order. This may include and is not limited to your name, credit card details, email address, mailing address and phone number. Only our authorised employees will have access to this information.

You can update your personal information by contacting us.

**Cookies**

Cookies are small files placed on your computer by a web page when you visit it. They can be used to store all sorts of useful information to make your next visit easier and more convenient, but some people are uncomfortable not knowing what information is in a cookie.

The PPP website uses cookies to compile statistics on the use of the various pages on our site and provide a unique user experience by tailoring advertisements you see. From time to time, we may use data collected from cookies to customise products and services we may offer you. When we send you emails, we include a web beacon to allow us to determine the number of people who open our emails. When you click on a link in an email, we may record this individual response to allow us to customise our offerings to you. Web beacons collect only limited information, such as a cookie identifier, time and date of a page being viewed, and a description of the page on which the Web Beacon resides (the URL).

Web Beacons can be refused when delivered via email. If you do not wish to receive Web Beacons via email, you will need to disable HTML images or refuse HTML (select Text only) emails via your email software.

When we send you emails we may also include tracking that identifies what marketing material you watch or read. This tracking makes you personally identifiable since we use your email address.

**How we use your personal information**

Your personal information may be used to:

  * Verify your identity when we are speaking with you;
  * Assist you to subscribe to our services and products;
  * Administer and manage our services, including charging and billing;
  * Research and develop our services;
  * Promote and market services and products to you. Where we do so, we will always provide you with an opportunity to let us know if you do not wish to receive marketing and promotions from us.

If some or all of the personal information we require is not collected, we may be unable to efficiently provide you with the services you require. ****

**Who can access my personal information?**

Only authorised employees of PPP have access to any information you provide. We may turn over any pertinent information to any legal or regulatory authority that has a demonstrable right and takes the proper steps to access it. We may also, if necessary, provide your personal information to our lawyers, accountants, auditors and other third parties (such as but not limited to IT providers) who provide services to us or act on our behalf, for the purposes of giving effect to the services you request from us, to improve support and provide a better, more relevant experience for you _,_ or as necessary to conduct our business.

Where your personal information is disclosed, it is provided through secure, encrypted e-mails to reputable third parties and __ we will ensure that the information is to be held, used or disclosed consistently with the Australian Privacy Principles.

If you inquire about one of your subscriptions, we may ask you to submit some additional information only to verify your identity. Remember, in this case we only ask you to confirm information you have already given us.

You have the right to contact us and ask what information we may hold about you. Before you can obtain access to any information held by PPP about you, your identity will first need to be verified. A fee may apply for such access.

**What if some of the information held is incorrect?  
**  
We endeavor to keep all information about you up-to-date. If any information held is incorrect please contact us.

**Consent to use and disclosure of your personal information**

PPP is a member of the global network of Agora companies, a company located in Baltimore, Maryland, USA. By subscribing to a PPP service you consent to being sent news and offers related to your subscription or that may suit your interests by PPP, related companies and carefully selected organisations. On occasions, PPP may provide your mailing address to third parties for direct marketing purposes. If at any time you do not wish your mailing address to be used for direct marketing or receive news and offers from carefully selected organisations, please contact us directly by email, post or phone. It is a requirement that all newsletters, updates and special reports be sent electronically. If you no longer wish to receive these services you may cancel your subscription at any time.

We may occasionally send you marketing emails. Our email marketing is permission based. If you received a mailing from us, it is because you are a subscriber or have otherwise consented to the terms of this privacy policy. You may unsubscribe at any time by post, by phone, or by clicking the unsubscribe link at the bottom of each email. We do not rent or sell email addresses to companies outside the PPP Group.

**Personal information and data security**

Your data is stored on our behalf on Agora Inc’s databases and servers located in the US, so it is necessary to disclose your personal information to Agora Inc for this purpose. PPP ensures all data collected is protected and secure against unauthorised access, alteration or deletion. Any data you submit to us through an online order form is transferred to us via a Secure Sockets Layer — an encryption protocol — and is kept in databases that cannot be accessed from outside our firewall. Our firewall is a mechanism that prevents access to our servers by anyone outside of the company.

The PPP website and e-mails may contain links to third party websites. Should you choose to click these links please be aware that our privacy policy will no longer apply. Please read and understand the privacy policy of the third party website before continuing further.

**Google  Updates**

Starting from 15 May 2017,  where users have chosen to enable Google to associate their web and app browsing history with their Google account, and to use information from their Google account to personalise ads, Google will use data from its signed-in users together with your Google Analytics data to build audience lists for cross-device remarketing.

Google Analytics will collect Google-authenticated identifiers associated with users’ Google Accounts and will temporarily join these identifiers to our Google Analytics data

Please note that all Google users can control their ads experience (or opt out of personalised ads altogether) at [My Account](http://myaccount.google.com/).

**Updates to our privacy policy**

PPP will review and update this privacy policy as needed. Please check back regularly for any updates.

**Privacy concerns or complaints**

If you have concerns or wish to make a complaint regarding the handling of your personal information by us, please contact us. We will promptly investigate your complaint and notify you of the outcome. If you are still not satisfied with the outcome of your complaint, you may in some cases refer your complaint to the Financial Ombudsman Service (tel. 1300 780 808, web www.fos.org.au), or the Office of the Australian Information Commissioner (tel. 1300 363 992, web www.oaic.gov.au).

**How to contact us**

If you have any questions regarding our privacy policy you can reach us here:

Port Phillip Publishing Pty Ltd,  
96-98 Bridport Street, Albert Park, VIC 3206

Ph: 1300 667 481 or +61 3 9037 8309

Email:[cs@portphillippublishing.com.au](mailto:cs@portphillippublishing.com.au)

Our registered address is:  
Port Phillip Publishing Pty Ltd,  
96–98 Bridport Street,  
Albert Park, VIC 3206  
Australia

**Copyright 2019 Port Phillip Publishing Pty Ltd. All rights reserved. No portion of this website may be reproduced, copied or in any way reused without the written persmision of Port Phillip Publishing.**

© Copyright 2006 - 2019 - Port Phillip Publishing.

All rights reserved. (ACN: 117 765 009) (AFS Licence: 323 988).

Content of this site may not be redistributed without the express written consent of Port Phillip Publishing Pty Ltd.
